[{"id": "5c90cf4b52800b05cac20f08", "question": "What US state is nicknamed \"The Ocean State\"?", "answer": "Rhode Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6014c65bfbde8045e48466b6", "question": "What liquid is known as the \"universal solvent\".", "answer": "Water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ff7", "question": "On what TV show did Roger Moore replace James Garner?", "answer": "Maverick", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60136fc1138175489539637b", "question": "What item gives the Green Lantern his power?", "answer": "Ring -- Turns out the key to being one of the most powerful superheroes in the DC universe is the ability to accessorize.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bad3", "question": "An English fire hydrant is said to be the inspiration behind the unique bottle of what liquor brand?", "answer": "Tanqueray", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae77", "question": "To what tribe did Chief Tecumseh belong?", "answer": "Shawnee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a4a94db61d1b4d384d5d672", "question": "Who created Popeye?", "answer": "Elzie Segar", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9c0", "question": "Which Nintendo character made the line \"Do a barrel roll!\" famous?", "answer": "Peppy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febbafc7e83c707845b2148", "question": "Who played the lead in \"The Last Boy Scout\"?", "answer": "Bruce Willis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b107", "question": "How many Americans from the US Embassy in Iran were taken hostage in November, 1979?", "answer": "63", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c20b", "question": "Why were the 1916 Olympic Games cancelled?", "answer": "Due to World War I", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff516f0ff04d658268c92f7", "question": "Egyptian workers were often paid with a ration of what?", "answer": "Beer (It was so beloved in Ancient Egypt that it was an accepted form of currency.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600f74cfa9e54d890926f700", "question": "What is banned in public places in Florida after 6 pm on a Thursday?", "answer": "Flatulence (farting)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c0d", "question": "What novel won Alice Walker a Pulitzer Prize in 1983?", "answer": "The Color Purple", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fffa1c173838c5c8a417f1c", "question": "How much more blood does a pregnant woman's body contain?", "answer": "The amount can increase by as much as 50% or more.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a367", "question": "What US city had the first subway?", "answer": "Boston", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c612", "question": "On a map, the vertical lines are called what?", "answer": "Longitude", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac80", "question": "Which saint is said to have landed in Ireland in 432 AD?", "answer": "St. Patrick", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395f4", "question": "In The Simpsons, what sits next to the basement door in the Simpson's house?", "answer": "Grandfather clock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e56", "question": "Of what famous family are Pongo and Perdita the parents?", "answer": "The 101 Dalmatians", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c34b", "question": "Which letter in the Greek alphabet is a circle with a horizontal dash through the center?", "answer": "Theta", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b51f", "question": "What does the abbreviation HTML stand for?", "answer": "HyperText Markup Language", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133958d", "question": "What song did Wayne and Garth listen to on their way to the doughnut shop in the movie \"Wayne's World\"?", "answer": "Bohemian Rhapsody", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afa3", "question": "Which British telephone number first came into use in 1937?", "answer": "999", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ca", "question": "What year did Jean Anouilh write the play \"The Lark\"?", "answer": "1952", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c4d", "question": "What year was Robert Downey Jr.'s first movie, \"Pound\" released in?", "answer": "1970", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c989", "question": "Macrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Long waits", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7cb", "question": "What republic is located between Lithuania and Estonia?", "answer": "Latvia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ee2", "question": "Aron and Caleb Trask are twins in what novel?", "answer": "East of Eden", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d1185a4fea7fe947a22284", "question": "By what name is Lignite often referred to as?", "answer": "Brown coal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beee", "question": "What are people encouraged to kiss under?", "answer": "Mistletoe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aed2", "question": "By what name is El-Hajj Malik El-Shabazz better known?", "answer": "Malcolm X", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7a9", "question": "How many US state capital cities lie on the Mississippi River?", "answer": "Two - Baton Rouge and St. Paul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba19", "question": "What football championship was first played in 1967?", "answer": "Super Bowl", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a066", "question": "What was the name of John Lennon and Cynthia Lennon's son?", "answer": "Julian", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bbc92f460f0007efaba0e59", "question": "What is the name of Roy Rogers' horse?", "answer": "Trigger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcec", "question": "What Internet search engine runs the Babel Fish translation service?", "answer": "AltaVista", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133961d", "question": "Who starred as Connor Macleod in the 1986 movie \"Highlander\"?", "answer": "Christopher Lambert", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd7947e83c707845b2173", "question": "What popular movie musical, directed by John Huston, was released in 1982?", "answer": "\"Annie\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fd4", "question": "What TV show did \"Family Matters\" spin off from?", "answer": "Perfect Strangers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2b7", "question": "What is the most common reference material when measuring the Specific Gravity of a substance?", "answer": "Water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5af98453aeb0982ee455954b", "question": "A nonagon is a shape that has how many sides?", "answer": "9", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8a0", "question": "How many minutes does it take to complete a 12 round boxing match?", "answer": "47 minutes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e9", "question": "What was writer and war hero T.E. Lawrence popularly known as?", "answer": "Lawrence of Arabia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f7519a9e54d890926f704", "question": "What is zucchini called in the UK?", "answer": "Courgette -- Zucchini/courgette is a variety of cucurbit, belonging to the same family as cucumber, squash, and melon.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394f9", "question": "What Ridley Scott movie features Tom Cruise trying to save the last unicorn?", "answer": "Legend", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338911", "question": "What was the name of the cat in Walt Disney's movie \"Cinderella\"?", "answer": "Lucifer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6010c8a50775fa611bce67e2", "question": "\"Veni, vidi, vici\" is a Latin phrase that translates to what?", "answer": "\"I came, I saw, I conquered\" -- Roman emperor Julius Caesar said this Latin phrase, as cited in Plutarch's \"Life of Caesar\".", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c772", "question": "Which planet is named for the Roman God who was the son of Juno and Jupiter?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef5c596ce05a3942286e1f", "question": "What did the Crocodile swallow in Peter Pan?", "answer": "An alarm clock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb52", "question": "What is the topmost part of a column called?", "answer": "Capital", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd78", "question": "What was the home country of famed jeweller Peter Carl Faberge?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9ad", "question": "What mountain is the tallest point in Argentina?", "answer": "Aconcagua", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefbebf6ce05a3942286ef6", "question": "What famous singer was nicknamed \"Ol' Blue Eyes\"?", "answer": "Frank Sinatra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1f1", "question": "What year did Volkswagen debut the Golf?", "answer": "1974", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb06", "question": "Since 1949, what magazine has handed out the most prestigious \"Car of the Year\" Award?", "answer": "Motor Trend", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaf6", "question": "Which country borders Kyrgystan to the southwest?", "answer": "Tajikistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bea6", "question": "What hobby uses the Yoshizawa-Randlett diagramming system?", "answer": "Origami", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a427", "question": "In what country would you find Mount Everest?", "answer": "Nepal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d3c", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"War & Peace\"?", "answer": "Leo Tolstoy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a461", "question": "The Angkor Wat temple is featured on what Asian country's flag?", "answer": "Cambodia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391af", "question": "Who dramatically kissed Halle Berry on stage when he won Best Actor?", "answer": "Adrien Brody", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e7", "question": "Bill Cosby is a famous alumnus of what Philadelphia university?", "answer": "Temple University", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abaf", "question": "Annapolis is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Maryland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e0f", "question": "Who was the only woman to hold the title office in the \"Book of Judges\"?", "answer": "Deborah", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a729", "question": "Springfield is the capital of which state?", "answer": "Illinois", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef93616ce05a3942286e8d", "question": "NFL footballs are made out of which material?", "answer": "Cowhide", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c061", "question": "What is the nickname of the patient in the game \"Operation\"?", "answer": "Cavity Sam", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b394", "question": "Which Apollo mission carried Neil Armstrong and his team to the Moon?\u00a0", "answer": "Apollo 11", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a31b", "question": "Who played the role of Jack Tripper on the TV show \"Three's Company\"?", "answer": "John Ritter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0ce", "question": "What sport is the Heisman Trophy awarded in?", "answer": "American college football", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c716", "question": "What astronomical unit of distance equals about 5.88 trillion miles?", "answer": "1 light year", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133945f", "question": "How does Jack die in the movie \"The Shining\"?", "answer": "He freezes to death", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a87e", "question": "What country was called the Gold Coast prior to its 1957 independence?", "answer": "Ghana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c595", "question": "What part of the body does a Rhinologist specialize in?", "answer": "The nose", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392ae", "question": "Who signed off his radio show by saying \"Keep your feet on the ground and keep reaching for the stars\"?", "answer": "Casey Kasem", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60136faa1381754895396379", "question": "In 2000, what character was elected U.S. President in the DC universe?", "answer": "Lex Luthor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bad5", "question": "What first name is the Russian equivalent of John?", "answer": "Ivan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b562", "question": "What is the largest cultivated crop in the United States?", "answer": "Corn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb5e", "question": "Which book of the Bible recounts the story of Noah and the Ark?", "answer": "Genesis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a36b", "question": "What country administers Greenland?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b27c", "question": "Who used hypnotism to treat the hemophilia of Tsarevich Alexei?", "answer": "Rasputin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febd50a7e83c707845b2162", "question": "In the Hunger Games films, which two actors portray Haymitch Abernathy and Effie Trinket?", "answer": "Woody Harrelson and Elizabeth Banks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9f7", "question": "What is the name of Nintendo's first video game console?", "answer": "Color TV Game", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bed7", "question": "What are the stars in traditional Cornish Stargazy pie?", "answer": "Pilchards eyes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f20", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Rosemary Murphy and Jennifer Jason Leigh?", "answer": "Dorothy Parker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ca3e0044f0f6af5b066643", "question": "Andorra is bordered by which two countries?", "answer": "France and Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fb1c06af497e33de805791c", "question": "What baseball announcer was famous for this signature phrase: \"Holy Cow!\"?", "answer": "Harry Caray", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60173f9544491cbd7c5a17b3", "question": "What was the name Chuck Yeager gave to the Bell X-1 plane he used to break the sound barrier?", "answer": "\"Glamorous Glennis\" -- The plane was nicknamed after his wife.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398cb", "question": "What 1968 movie starred Jack Lemmon and Walter Matthau sharing an apartment?", "answer": "The Odd Couple", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339651", "question": "What kind of animal is the title character in the 1998 movie \"Paulie\"?", "answer": "Parrot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fec", "question": "Thomas Harris created what character?", "answer": "Hannibal Lecter", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8ca", "question": "The NASDAQ stock market is based in what US city?", "answer": "New York", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b766", "question": "The phrase \"sticky wickeet\" has its origins in what sport?", "answer": "Cricket", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010c9250775fa611bce67e8", "question": "What is hummus made from?", "answer": "Chickpeas -- Hummus is Arabic for \"chickpeas.\" It is a Middle Eastern dish common throughout the Mediterranean region and beyond.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a88b", "question": "What capital city is built around the famous Plaza Mayor and Puerta del Sol?", "answer": "Madrid", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdffc091cf6db9ac4808cfb", "question": "Which country is home to the language with the world's shortest alphabet?", "answer": "Papua New Guinea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b4b101dd7bf43be5e7c5", "question": "What's the age limit for horses competing in the Kentucky Derby?", "answer": "3-years-old", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bd8", "question": "In Arthurian legend, what was the name of King Arthur's magic sword?", "answer": "Excalibur", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe77025eec85e375820b2f6", "question": "What is the world\u2019s most populous island?", "answer": "Java, Indonesia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5906820bff9c0647b50a8099", "question": "Who was the male lead in the 1976 film \"The Man Who Fell to Earth\"?", "answer": "David Bowie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9386a6bd93ce3a4e5f684", "question": "What cosmologist theorized the creation of the universe from quantum fluctuations?", "answer": "Alexander Vilenkin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a39b", "question": "Where is the Guggenheim Museum?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339034", "question": "The story \"The Rose and The Ring\" was written by which 19th century novelist?", "answer": "William Thackeray", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c270", "question": "What is February's birthstone?", "answer": "Amethyst", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe908a101dd7bf43be5e886", "question": "What vitamin does E. coli produce?", "answer": "K", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b45a", "question": "Who led over 900 followers in a mass suicide in 1978?", "answer": "Jim Jones", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dd0", "question": "What comedian has real-life twin sons named Matthew and Gregory?", "answer": "Ray Romano", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca1b", "question": "Filbert is an alternative name for which nut?", "answer": "Hazelnut", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b27", "question": "What 1991 River Phoenix/Keanu Reeves film took its title from lyrics in a B-52's song?", "answer": "My Own Private Idaho", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c31c", "question": "What does Afforestation mean?", "answer": "Planting of Trees", "category": "science"}, {"id": "594a64462ebb971c1417fba2", "question": "Who was the first woman to swim across Lake Ontario?", "answer": "Marilyn Bell", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefc3ae6ce05a3942286f26", "question": "John Paul Jones was the bassist and keyboardist for what rock band?", "answer": "Led Zeppelin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909d1a4bb53d1af65886503", "question": "Who wrote the 1958 book \"Journey to Christmas\"?", "answer": "B. J. Chute", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a330", "question": "What year did Belle and Sebastian originally release the album \"Tigermilk\"?", "answer": "1996", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecd67fec223966ae8f88d4", "question": "Who says, \"Frankly my dear, I don\u2019t give a damn\" in \"Gone with the Wind\"?", "answer": "Rhett Butler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ca", "question": "What year was the movie \"Aliens\" released?", "answer": "1986", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abf7", "question": "What is a resident of Manchester called?", "answer": "Mancunian", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c97d", "question": "What constellation is Polaris located in?", "answer": "Ursa Minor", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398a2", "question": "What was the longest-running musical on Broadway during the 20th century?", "answer": "Cats", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fb08642cf631c2414a13b54", "question": "In the TV show \"Friends\", what was Joey\u2019s nickname while working at Alessandro\u2019s?", "answer": "Dragon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c312", "question": "The popular caterpillar sushi roll features unagi, the Japanese word for what type of sea creature?", "answer": "Eel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0e1", "question": "What was the better known nickname of 19th century figure Joseph Merrick?", "answer": "The Elephant Man", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6bb", "question": "The logo of Mack Trucks is what animal?", "answer": "A bulldog", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af1a", "question": "Which US president was better known as \"Ike\"?", "answer": "Dwight D. Eisenhower", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389cc", "question": "What animal's head is placed on a stick in \"Lord of the Flies\"?", "answer": "A pig's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febba977e83c707845b2145", "question": "What was the first Super Bowl to use Roman numerals in its title?", "answer": "Super Bowl V", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c482", "question": "Are polar bears carnivores or omnivores?", "answer": "Carnivores", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397d9", "question": "How many Red Balloons did Nena have in the pop charts in 1984?", "answer": "99", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb57de5dad637d903c880c", "question": "What is the name of the oldest bridge in Venice, which crosses the city's famous Grand Canal?", "answer": "The Ponte di Rialto, or Rialto Bridge, was built between 1588 and 1591 to span the width of the Grand Canal.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7df", "question": "In which US state is Shenandoah National Park located?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4ea3606d333868d34d75a", "question": "In what year did Nazi Germany open its first concentration camp?", "answer": "1933", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff5169eff04d658268c92f1", "question": "What activist organized the \"March of the Mill Children\" from Philadelphia to President Teddy Roosevelt's summer home in 1903?", "answer": "Mary Harris Jones -- She organized the march to demand an end to child labour.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59524338736d4be723796b67", "question": "How many of the same item can you get in the term \"Bakers Dozen\"?", "answer": "13", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59067ecaff9c0647b50a807e", "question": "To what age did the US state of Hawaii change the legal smoking age on January 1, 2016?", "answer": "21", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b597", "question": "Where in New York is the 30 Rock building located?", "answer": "30 Rockefeller Center", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0c4", "question": "Who sang the song \"Beat It\"?", "answer": "Michael Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b619", "question": "Who was the first female to be featured on the front of a Wheaties box?", "answer": "Mary Lou Retton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399b3", "question": "What was Tom Cruise\u2019s character\u2019s name in the \"Mission Impossible\" movie series?", "answer": "Ethan Hunt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fbae3fc0738315b1fb74e1d", "question": "Who won Chelsea's Player of the Year in 2012 and 2013?", "answer": "Juan Mata", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b7ff9c53a3a814d89068c57", "question": "What unit of measurement is one tenth of a nautical mile?", "answer": "A Cable", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffa420fc73aa70ea0b70b13", "question": "Father Damien ministered to lepers on which Hawaiian Island?", "answer": "Molokai", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab89", "question": "Phnom Penh is the capital of which Asian country?", "answer": "Cambodia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe3ecab8b5801b8f54a7fae", "question": "What year did Castro launch the revolution against Batista?", "answer": "1956", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e803e2de59ea584496fea0", "question": "Which novel is the sequel to Dodie Smith's \"The Hundred and One Dalmatians\"?", "answer": "The Starlight Barking", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e38d000f6c8a670a7957c55", "question": "What is the name of the first single by the Korean girl-group \"Red Velvet\"?", "answer": "Happiness", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd74", "question": "What branch of philosophy deals with the end of the world?", "answer": "Eschatology", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5cefc089948005ec986edcdc", "question": "Who is the third member of the group LOONA to debut?", "answer": "Haseul", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58e2f5602e77afa695b03105", "question": "Mal\u00e9 is the capital of which Asian country?", "answer": "Maldives", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600b88aa1d8c1817608d53f5", "question": "In what sport did Fanny Chmelar compete for Germany during the 2010 Winter Olympic Games?", "answer": "Skiing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9e0", "question": "What does a monophobe fear?", "answer": "Being alone", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aed5", "question": "In what year was Billy the Kid born?", "answer": "1859", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5eb738c05e259d786908732f", "question": "Who was the first Roman Emperor?", "answer": "Augustus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bac5", "question": "What year was National Geographic magazine first published?", "answer": "1888", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133924b", "question": "Who performed the Bond theme song \"Die Another Day\"?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9f3", "question": "What do you have if you suffer from podobromhidrosis?", "answer": "Smelly feet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5feddc886ce05a3942286d9d", "question": "What is the name of the spaceship the crew of astronauts uses in the film \"Interstellar\"?", "answer": "The Endurance", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392e9", "question": "What are the names of the seven dwarfs in Disney's \"Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs\"?", "answer": "Dopey, Grumpy, Doc, Bashful, Sleepy, Sneezy, Happy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f13", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Cate Blanchett and Judi Dench?", "answer": "Queen Elizabeth I", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e7b506d333868d34d741", "question": "In 1929, what did Clarence Birdseye introduce?", "answer": "Frozen food", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c558", "question": "What is the common name for \"graphospasm\"?", "answer": "Writer's cramp", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4c6", "question": "Where is Mount Olympus?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339176", "question": "Which Seinfeld creator plays himself in the TV show \"Curb Your Enthusiasm\"?", "answer": "Larry David", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015debafe83fe1f2a824b71", "question": "What weapon was developed in 1942 in a secret laboratory at Harvard University?", "answer": "Napalm", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d7", "question": "Luzon and Mindanao are the two largest islands of what country?", "answer": "The Philippines", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339377", "question": "How many Oscars did the 1997 movie \"Titanic\" win?", "answer": "11", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dd9", "question": "What working title for the movie \"Scream\" later named a hit 2000 film?", "answer": "Scary Movie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffcfaed9dc5ec6cd98a8313", "question": "What does Italian artist Maurizio Savini make sculptures out of?", "answer": "Chewing gum -- He aims to remember childhood and personal memories by sculpting\u00a0pink chewing gum\u00a0and fiberglass.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59f9b9f6364247bf200fb893", "question": "What is a \"Shoal\"?", "answer": "A group of fish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58b371201c3f17ccc40c8e1d", "question": "Considered to be the oldest pub in the US, what year was the White Horse Tavern of Rhode Island opened in?", "answer": "1673", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acfd", "question": "What is widely considered to be man's first celestial observatory?", "answer": "Stonehenge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d72", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"The Modern Prometheus\"?", "answer": "Frankenstein", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8ab4d01dd7bf43be5e767", "question": "What part of the computer does \"QWERTY\" refer to?", "answer": "The keyboard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e6b653fb6c85e9e634ff48", "question": "The fear of men is known as what?", "answer": "Androphobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133911f", "question": "What novel about social conventions did E. M. Forster publish in 1910?", "answer": "Howards End", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9f9", "question": "In which South American country is the Atacama desert?", "answer": "Chile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59db76d20ab2c8f322317fe7", "question": "In which ocean or sea are the Seychelles?", "answer": "Indian Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339855", "question": "Totoro from the movie \"My Neighbor Totoro\" lives in what kind of tree?", "answer": "Camphor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c248", "question": "Which is larger, the U.S. gallon or the Imperial gallon?", "answer": "The Imperial", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1f2", "question": "What year did Volkswagen start production of the Golf?", "answer": "1974", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b88a01dd7bf43be5e7ec", "question": "Vultures gathering on the side of the road to eat are called what?", "answer": "A wake", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398da", "question": "What TV series starred trail hands Gil Favor and Rowdy Yates?", "answer": "Rawhide", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe527561bf59ab7d2e380f9", "question": "What is the largest number of children to be born in a single birth and survive?", "answer": "8", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909d179bb53d1af65886502", "question": "What is Clark planning on spending his Christmas bonus in the movie \"National Lampoon\u2019s Christmas Vacation\"?", "answer": "Swimming pool", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdfbf4b003d27d341092bd4", "question": "Which country holds the record for both the coldest and hottest temperatures in South America?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fde4e92c6c6b019850c9a85", "question": "What was the name of the anti-Castro group at the \"Bay of Pigs\"?", "answer": "La Brigada", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dda", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"ukulele\"?", "answer": "Hawaiian", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b89", "question": "What film marked Julie Andrews first starring role?", "answer": "Mary Poppins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3b4", "question": "Which Major League hitter drove in the most runs in a single season between 1980-89?", "answer": "Don Mattingly", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7cce3877e98cb97778a2e", "question": "Which country is known by its inhabitants as Suomi?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597cdaaae347d002c297e4d6", "question": "What nationality is Yehudi Menuhin?", "answer": "American", "category": "general"}, {"id": "591c37bc815febcc896f9273", "question": "What is the tenth sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Capricorn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea82e4ff048f679a45ac24", "question": "How many zeros are in a quadrillion?", "answer": "15", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015fcbffe83fe1f2a824c44", "question": "The founder of Atari also founded which pizza restaurant?", "answer": "Chuck E. Cheese", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1d7", "question": "Who traditionally occupied the Peacock Throne?", "answer": "The shah of Iran", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6008de2df4f3bc4a292f8628", "question": "Who stated, \"Injustice anywhere is a threat to justice everywhere\".", "answer": "Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. (He wrote it in his famous open letter known as \"Letter from Birmingham Jail\".)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f3057905aa2bc17b61b2ad1", "question": "What is the fear of smells or odors known as?", "answer": "Osmophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7ae", "question": "What is added to copper to make bronze?", "answer": "Tin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e14cfe83fe1f2a824b93", "question": "What best describes Germany\u2019s standard invasion strategy at the beginning of World War II?", "answer": "Attack with a combination of speed and overwhelming force (blitzkrieg)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad47", "question": "Harry Truman was known as \"the Haberdasher\" because of what?", "answer": "His previous occupation", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6cf", "question": "What doctor invented a device called the Mercitron?", "answer": "Dr. Jack Kevorkian", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febae847e83c707845b20f6", "question": "Which insect uses the Milky Way to navigate?", "answer": "African dung beetle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c582", "question": "What general color does skin turn as a result of jaundice?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff51aafff04d658268c9308", "question": "Who was Telemachus?", "answer": "Telemachus was the only son of Odysseus and Penelope.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a089", "question": "Who plays The Car in the TV show \"Red Dwarf\"?", "answer": "Danny John-Jules", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa3df6ce05a3942286eac", "question": "Which Oscar-winner studied opera as a teen?", "answer": "Meryl Streep", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133951f", "question": "Who provided the voice for Captain John Smith in Disney's 1995 movie \"Pocahontas\"?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ac1", "question": "The book \"The Second Sex\" was written by who?", "answer": "Simone de Beauvoir", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133908f", "question": "Who is the Roman equivalent of the Greek goddess Eirene?", "answer": "Pax", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2f6", "question": "What union did Jimmy Hoffa head until his 1975 disappearance?", "answer": "The Teamsters", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60062c98c9d816e292245c2d", "question": "What kind of cans did Andy Warhol famously paint?", "answer": "Campbell's Soup Cans\u00a0is a work of art consisting of 32 canvases, each painted with a Campbell's Soup can.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4b6cf06d333868d34d6f5", "question": "Who assumed power as Prime Minister of Libya in 1970?", "answer": "Muammar Al-Gaddafi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a7", "question": "Who played Mad Max Rockatansky?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c38b", "question": "What is the name for a human third molar?", "answer": "A wisdom tooth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b05c", "question": "The National Geographic Society was founded in 1888, in which US city?", "answer": "Washington, D.C.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfde", "question": "How many tournaments make up a Grand Slam in golf?", "answer": "4\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b174565bb2d29f81593b701", "question": "Who was the lead singer of the British-American rock band \"Foreigner\"?", "answer": "Lou Gramm", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe698b420565ad31a57c737", "question": "Which goddess helped guide Odysseus back home?", "answer": "Athena", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad62", "question": "What union was behind the \"Look for the Union Label\" advertising campaign?\"", "answer": "International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339394", "question": "What TV show do Thelma and Louise want to avoid being on?", "answer": "Geraldo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1c3", "question": "On what island was Napoleon born?", "answer": "Corsica", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600cc6536de0eb824d4052f7", "question": "What is the official state fruit of New Hampshire?", "answer": "Pumpkin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399d1", "question": "What 1980\u2019s and 1990\u2019s law drama was set at the firm of McKenzie-Brackman when it premiered?", "answer": "L.A. Law", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ace4", "question": "How many stones make up each of Stonehenge's trilithons?", "answer": "Three", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef93096ce05a3942286e8a", "question": "In what substance is Han Solo frozen in the film \"The Empire Strikes Back\"?", "answer": "Carbonite", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133895a", "question": "What musical is based on the book \"Anna and the King of Siam\"?", "answer": "The King and I", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394e8", "question": "Who played Simon Templar in the 1960's TV show \"The Saint\"?", "answer": "Roger Moore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b409", "question": "What year did the US issue a patent on the production of margarine?", "answer": "1871", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e3f4ae5cb9e8bda6821369", "question": "Approximatly when did construction of the Colosseum finish?", "answer": "80 AD", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58dba239874c93a3298b2130", "question": "Who wasn't afraid to call James Joyce \"a greasy undergraduate\"?", "answer": "Virginia Wolfe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ad0", "question": "Which author set most of his book in the year 802,701?", "answer": "H.G. Wells", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aeb", "question": "The Christmas carol \"Jingle Bells\" was first published in what year?", "answer": "1857", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ae95a3574a5ce6b56b8257", "question": "What are formed by Orogeny?", "answer": "Mountains", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fede4e26ce05a3942286de3", "question": "Who recorded the hit single \"Sussudio\" in 1985?", "answer": "Phil Collins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc8b", "question": "Who did the Chicago Bears fire in 1992, just four years after he was the NFL Coach of the Year?", "answer": "Mike Ditka", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4d964408b8581f80b092a5", "question": "How old did Canada turn on July 1, 2017?", "answer": "150 years old", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5eb73d495e259d7869087334", "question": "In what year did the Kentucky Derby start?", "answer": "1875", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1df", "question": "The single \"Up Where We Belong\" is taken from which film?", "answer": "An Officer and a Gentleman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4b0a49076251badbeac0", "question": "What was Dwight D. Eisenhower's major campaign slogan during the 1952 presidential election?", "answer": "\"I like Ike\" -- Ike was Eisenhower's nickname.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdc0c3d469bb8041d07a04f", "question": "Who is considered \"The Father of Modern French Cooking\"?", "answer": "August Escoffier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdffce41cf6db9ac4808d05", "question": "What is the capital of Bavaria?", "answer": "Munich", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59f9b770364247bf200fb872", "question": "Which 1993 Disney movie starred Bette Midler as a witch?", "answer": "Hocus Pocus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c8a60690aac110e4167079", "question": "What year did the Boston Tea Party take place?", "answer": "1773", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c70b", "question": "How many calories must you burn to lose one pound?", "answer": "3500", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339125", "question": "\"Samson and Delilah\" is an opera by which French composer?", "answer": "Camille Saint-Sa\u00ebns", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4eac106d333868d34d75c", "question": "What was the first Nazi concentration camp?", "answer": "Dachau (Nohra opened in March 1933 as a re-education center. Dachau opened after and became a model for future death camps and is considered to be the first)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e338fe83fe1f2a824ba9", "question": "Why was the Japanese capture of Rangoon such a bitter loss for the Allies?", "answer": "As a major seaport, it was an excellent supply point", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e321fe83fe1f2a824ba7", "question": "What was the focus of the Tehran Conference?", "answer": "The Allied invasion of France.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea41d8ff048f679a45ab72", "question": "Which breed did the English call a coach dog", "answer": "Dalmatian", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d2f", "question": "Bernard Marx and Lenina Crowne are the main characters of what novel?", "answer": "A Brave New World", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c955", "question": "In distance measuring, what does AU stand for?", "answer": "Astronomical Unit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe771aceec85e375820b2fc", "question": "What strait separates Australia's mainland from Tasmania?", "answer": "Bass Strait", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b85", "question": "What is the name of the rabbit in the movie \"Bambi\"?", "answer": "Thumper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fedd8d66ce05a3942286d75", "question": "Where is the headquarters of Nintendo?", "answer": "Kyoto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7e6", "question": "In what city is Gonzaga University located?", "answer": "Spokane, Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c90a", "question": "Which continent is the natural habitat of the Ostrich?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "science"}]